Dig the life fantastic!
Fantastic Mr. Fox is a adventure, animation,
comedy film directed by Wes Anderson.
The Fantastic Mr.
Fox, bored with his current life, plans a heist against the three local farmers.
The farmers, tired of sharing their chickens with the sly
fox, seek revenge against him and his family.
Mr. Fox (voice), played by George Clooney.
Walter Boggis (voice), played by Robin Hurlstone.
Felicity Fox (voice), played by Meryl Streep.
Ash Fox (voice), played by Jason Schwartzman.
Kristofferson Silverfox (voice), played by Eric Chase Anderson.
Kylie (voice), played by Wallace Wolodarsky.
Fantastic Mr.
Fox is a 2009 stop-motion animated adventure comedy film directed by Wes Anderson (in his animation debut) from a
screenplay by Anderson and Noah Baumbach and based on the novel of the same name by Roald Dahl.
Featuring stop-motion animation, it stars George Clooney, Meryl Streep,
Jason Schwartzman, Bill Murray, Willem Dafoe, and Owen Wilson.
In the film, a spree of thefts led by Mr.
Fox (Clooney) results in his family, and later his
community, being hunted down by three farmers.
Development on the project began in 2004 as a collaboration between Anderson and Henry Selick
under Revolution Studios; by 2007, Revolution and Selick left for other projects.
Work on Fantastic Mr.
Fox was moved to 20th Century Fox, where production began in
2007 on Stage C of 3 Mills Studios in London.
In addition to an original score by Alexandre Desplat, the
soundtrack includes several songs from other artists.
Fantastic Mr.
Fox premiered as the opening film of the 53rd BFI London Film Festival on October 14, 2009, and was released in the United Kingdom on October 23
and United States on November 13, to critical acclaim, with praise for its humor, stop-motion animation and Anderson's direction.
However, it underperformed at the box office, grossing
$58.1 million against a $40 million budget.
The film received Academy Award nominations for Best Animated
Feature and Best Original Score, but lost both to Up.
It is now considered to be among the best animated films of the 21st century.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
tree, peasant, fox, affectation.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking and intense.